AMY DYSON

13162 Capstone Drive, San Diego, CA 92130 ❖ H 858.847.2111 ❖ C 858.776.1473 ❖ amydyson@studiowest.com

Professional Summary

A results-driven, articulate and analytical Software Developer who works well with a team. Equipped with 6 years experience in microprocessor hardware and software and 2 years in web design and SEO. Excels at communicating complex ideas in simple language. Interested in a challenging technical career in web development.

Education

Chatham College	LEARN Academy
BA, Computer Science & English Literature	Full stack web development with Ruby on Rails
UC Davis Extension SEO Program	UCSD Extension Certificate in Teaching Online
Skills	
• JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS	• Node.js, React
• Ruby on Rails, MVC frameworks	 Technical Training & Writing
• JSON, AJAX	 Instructional Design & Graphic Design
◆ Test Driven Development, Heroku	◆ SEO
Work History	

Work History

Studio West and The Recording Arts Center, 2005 to Present (Co-Owner)

- Cofounder of TRAC, which grew from startup to \$1M in revenue over an eight year period
- ◆ Designed two business websites and implemented SEO 25% increase in inquiries
- Continuously improve wide range of business processes, including cutting A/R from 30% to 2%
- Wrote, designed, and published TRAC school catalog in compliance with CA standards
- Manage marketing and advertising campaigns, including blogs, social media, e-blasts, & print ads
- Manage variety of business needs including audits, travel arrangements, and IT for staff emails

Freelance Writer and Journalist, 1996 to Present

Highlights include:

- Wrote Motorola Time Processing Unit (TPU) microcoding textbook used by automotive engineers
- Regularly edit technical documents for DoGav Systems Ltd., consultants based in Israel
- Edited 100-page advocacy guide for the United Nation's Roll Back Malaria Partnership
- Regular contributor to a Texas sports magazine—interviewed and wrote profiles on athletes

Instructional Designer & Trainer, Motorola, 1991 to 1996

- Worked with subject matter experts to design new microprocessor courses quickly
- Taught microprocessor courses to customers in the US and internationally
- Developed microcoding course that created new opportunities for Motorola and other companies
- Received consistently high performance ratings and still in contact with several key partners



13162 Capstone Drive, San Diego, CA 92130 ❖ H 858.847.2111 ❖ C 858.776.1473 ❖ amydyson@studiowest.com

Projects

JavaScript

At LEARN Academy, I designed a battleship game with a partner. I took that core code and greatly expanded its complexity, adding an artificial intelligence portion so that the player is competing against the computer. This took a lot of logic to make sure that the computer "player" mimicked the restrictions that the human player had, reacting to the *view* and not the *model*. I also added styling and sound to make it fun. My biggest challenge was figuring out why the program went into an infinite loop about 15% of the time during the check to make sure the ships don't touch. It turned out to be a big picture issue: with the spacing restrictions I had imposed, sometimes the ships didn't all fit on the board. I softened the restrictions somewhat, and added a timeout of the loop just in case. I had spent countless hours looking in the details but had to stand back to solve the problem.

Ruby on Rails

Developed a Garage Sale Finder application as a group project. For people looking for garage sales, the app will find garage sales by city or zipcode, and show them on a Google map. It allows search for individual items within the selected geographical area. For those hosting garage sales, the app allows them to create an account and list a garage sale, with individual items and photos listed. The app shows only future garage sales. It checks and deletes any sale in the past, so the site is automatically kept orderly and organized.

As an intern for Notch8, currently updating an application called "reumanager" into a multi-tenant SAAS app. The application manages the application process for research experiences for undergraduates (REUs) for UCSD and other institutions. Currently, Notch8 manually must upload and host a new app for each REU. We're converting it for a smoother experience and less work for Notch8. We've added a gem called Apartment, which establishes each REU as a separate "tenant". We're now updating the flow and are adding a React-based form for a better user experience.

Web Design

Designed websites for Studio West, The Recording Arts Center, Studio West Design, PersonalizeDx Labs, Keith Methven Music, and the band Kick Up the Dust.